



Sokolov Mikhael

Male, 25 years old, born on 10 July 1995

+7 (906) 7474274

sokomishalov@mail.ru — preferred means of communication

Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/sokomishalov Another site: https://github.com/sokomishalov

Reside in: Moscow, metro station Bagrationovskaya

Citizenship: Russia, work permit at: Russia Ready to relocate, ready for business trips

Desired position and salary

Senior/Lead Full stack developer

IT, Internet, Telecom

- · Banking Software
- Software Development
- Project Management

Employment: project work, full time

Work schedule: remote working, flexible schedule, full day Desired travel time to work: from hour to one and half

Work experience — 5 years 4 months

August 2019 — till

now

1 year 4 months

VTB

Moscow, www.vtbcareer.com

Leading software architect

Design and development of backend and frontend applications

January 2019 — August 2019 8 months **Sberbank**

Moscow, www.sbrf.ru

Chief IT-engineer

Development of backend and frontend applications

July 2018 — January 2019 7 months

Sberbank

Moscow, www.sbrf.ru

Leading IT-engineer

Development of backend and frontend applications

January 2018 — July 2018 7 months Sberbank Technology

Moscow

Leading IT-engineer

Development of backend and frontend applications

August 2017 — January 2018 6 months Sberbank Technology

Moscow

Senior IT-engineer

Development of backend and frontend applications

August 2015 — August 2017 2 years 1 month

Sberbank Technology

Moscow

IT-engineer

Development of backend and frontend applications

Education

Higher

2017

Moscow Bauman State Technical University, Moscow

Robotics and complex automation, Systems of the Automated Designing

Key skills

Languages

Russian — Native

English — B2 — Upper Intermediate

Skills

Spring Framework HTML Oracle PI/SQL Java EE SQL MS SQL Server Apache Maven Hibernate ORM Java Database Android **JSP** CSS MS SQL **iQuery** JavaScript AngularJS PostgreSQL XML Linux Git MySQL Jenkins Ansible Docker Dart Flutter Reactor

Netty Kotlin

Driving experience

Own car

Driver's license category B

Further information

About me

I am a passionate developer, love hard tasks in my job.

During my job, I've learned quick execution of tasks of any kind. There were situations in my practice such as "Hey! We have to write a code generator for guys from outsourcing. Do it as fast as you can!" or "Hey! You have to write a new app! Demo starts in 2 hours"

Mostly I am a back-end developer on Kotlin/Java. I used to write exclusively on Java, but later I saw Kotlin. I truly love it and write about 90% of the backend code on Kotlin now.

I participated in a large number of projects, saw a lot of scary stuff (including legacy, unfortunately).

Almost all projects used Spring and its stack (God bless Jorgen Holler). Since the beginning of 2019, I prefer to write non-blocking code with spring-webflux and coroutines. Worked a lot with relational databases (PostgreSQL, Oracle, MSSQL, MySQL) and NoSQL (Redis, Mongo, Cassandra).

One day I've started to work with the front-end and it's very cool that this happened. It turned out that the frontend also has a lot of interesting things. Back in the days was JSP and plain JS (omg, that was horrible). Later we saw Angular and that was a few better than previous technologies. After a few projects on Angular, we wanted to try to write on React. That was in 2017 and since those days I use it in each project and I think React is pretty great!

At the end of 2018, I became interested in mobile development, in particular, Dart language and the Flutter framework (Google framework for writing cross-platform mobile applications). I think this framework is extremely promising and therefore very interesting for me. I also wrote a bit for Android (Kotlin/Java). There was a period of «perverse ties» with React Native.

There were situations when I had to be a DevOps engineer. So I've learned about Ansible and Jenkins, used to write playbooks and jobs for several projects. Worked a few with Gitlab CI.

I prefer to work on a mechanical keyboard and macOS (well, I approve Linux) and with two screens (one exclusively for the IDE, another for StackOverflow, messengers, and other stuff).